and these are the four decrees in fact
Nehemiah when he got to Jerusalem said
listen he told the Jews don't you know
that as long as this our work lays
desolate we are a reproach to God let us
rise up and finish the work Church we
got to get it together and somebody say
we mean let's say I want you to say
let's get it to gather we need to get it
together how many believe we need to get
it together all right I love a good
story but you know what I hate about
good stories
I hate when good stories get put on
pause and right now we're gonna put this
story on pause so just pause right there
where are we pausing what book are we in
Nehemiah let's pause right here now I
want to tell you another story it's the
story of the Bible it's an amazing story
but to tell you the story the Bible we
have to go to the book of Genesis it's
like you ready to go to the book of
Genesis don't turn in your Bibles just
focus on me all right
so where are we going everyone Genesis
all right very good now the book of
Genesis introduces us to a man by the
name of Adam amen the book of Genesis
introduces us to the creation of man
Adam but the Bible says that Adam is
actually the first Adam did you know
that Jesus Christ was a second out of
amen
so you have in the book of Genesis you
have the genesis of the first man but
actually the genesis of the first man is
kind of like a similar type of the
genesis of the second Adam Amen anybody
excited not really right it's like okay
what book comes after Genesis Exodus do
you know that the book of Exodus is
about a man who was drawn out of waters
goes into the wilderness for 40 years
and then returns to deliver his people
that's very interesting because the
second Adam Jesus Christ was also drawn
out of waters at his baptism went into
the wilderness for 40 days and then
returned to deliver his people
what book comes after Exodus
you know what the Book of Leviticus is
about The Book of Leviticus is about the
work of the priests in cleansing his
people from their sins that's very
interesting because Christ the second
Adam was also drawn out of waters goes
into the wilderness for forty days
returns to deliver his people and then
begins the work of cleansing his people
from their sins
what book comes after Leviticus very
interesting you know the Book of Numbers
is about the book of numbers is about
Moses leading the twelve and calling 70
well that's interesting because Jesus
the second Adam goes this drawn out of
water goes into the wilderness for forty
days returns to deliver his people
begins the work of cleansing them from
their sins and also calls twelve and
ordained seventy what book comes after
numbers well that's interesting because
the book of Deuteronomy is actually
Moses his final sermon at the end of
that book he calls together the twelve
tribes he repeats the covenant they sing
a song and then he goes out alone to die
by himself
but he dies is buried and resurrected
that's pretty interesting because Jesus
the second Adam who was drawn out of
waters who goes into the waters for
forty days returns to deliver his people
does the work of cleansing them from
their sins
Carles twelve ordained seventy also
gathered the twelve at the end of his
ministry repeats the Covenant they sing
a song and he goes out alone to die
by himself but he dies is buried and
resurrected yeah who would have thought
wait what what book comes after
Deuteronomy Joshua very interesting The
Book of Joshua is about a man who leads
who brings down a nation with a loud
shout just as Jesus Christ the second
Adam who is drawn out of waters goes
into the wilderness for forty days
return to deliver his people does the
work of cleansing their sins carl's
twelve ordained seventy gathers them
together repeats the song repeats the
Covenant goes out to die when he dies he
brings down the kingdom of Satan with a
loud shout it is finished that's pretty
interesting
but there's more because there's another
book that comes after the Book of Joshua
what book is that judge is very
interesting you know what the book of
Judges is about the book of Judges is
about the twelve tribes going forward to
conquer even though they no longer have
a physical leader very interesting
because after the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus the early church
who now no longer has a physical leader
like they did in Jesus Joshua now goes
forward conquering in the name of Christ
that's pretty interesting
what book comes after Josh after our
judges pretty interesting you know what
the Book of Ruth is about the Book of
Ruth is about the book of Hebrews is I'm
sorry the Book of Ruth is about a
Gentile woman with a Hebrew
mother-in-law this Gentile woman you
know what she's doing she is working in
the field bringing in the sheaves and by
the way Boaz who was a type of Christ is
looking at that woman like who is that
lady in the field who is that woman in
the field man it's right on this Silas
easy who is that woman working in the
field I'm attracted to that woman
working in the field that's the kind of
woman that Jesus likes a woman a church
working in the field bringing in the
sheaves and by the way she says of her
Hebrew mother-in-law your God will be my
god very interesting very interesting
but what comes after the Book of Ruth
first samuel that's interesting you know
what the book of 1st samuel was about
the book of 1st time i by the way we're
going somewhere with this ok there's a
point here the book of 1st Samuel is
about a nation the Israelite nation who
came up with a really crazy idea they
decided that they were going to reject
their high priest Samuel to have a king
rune over them instead and this King
would usurp the authority of the
priesthood in other words this King
would bring together in a sense church
and state very interesting because after
the church have been working for science
or for some time in the field and doing
their thing they did something very
interesting they rejected their high
priest Jesus Christ for a man named
Constantine who decided to join Church
and wow that's very good it's almost
like this history it's paralleling the
Old Testament now beloved after first
Samuel you have second Samuel you have
first and second Kings you have first
and second Chronicles which all detail
Israel's apostasy which by the way led
them to be taken captive by a kingdom
named mystery Wow why that parallels the
twelve hundred and sixty years who would
have thought that from Genesis to 2nd
chronicles would be in shadow form the
great controversy as we have understood
it in the book the great controversy
wait what but wait there's more
you see after ii chronicles remember ii
chronicles would symbolically bring us
down to what year 1798 end of the twelve
hundred and sixty years
alright so so partner here don't don't
jump ahead of me just think now whatever
book comes next
must have if we're going them on the
line must have some significance to some
major events that would happen after
1798 so i have a question for you what
book comes after second chronicles Ezra
you know we learned a little bit earlier
that there were three decrees
proclamations given in the book of Ezra
y'all are not feeling me three decrees